

Adam Matan

R&D Manager, developer, team leader, and public speaker. I lead teams that build modern apps on the cloud.

What do I bring to the table?

Team & As R&D Manager, developer and public speaker / DevRel, I deliver quality products, understand Business goals, and build productive communication between the dev team, company leadership, and customers. Done is better than perfect.

Dev Practical backend solutions using modern cloud tools - Serverless, AWS, Linux, Python and POSIX languages, and (NO)SQL DBs. GIS experience (PostGIS, GeoPy, QGIS etc.). I use Open-Source and Free Software to build robust products quickly. See my <u>StackOverflow</u>, <u>Servefault</u>, and GIS Stack exchange profiles.

Experience

2019- R&D Manager (Wix Code / Corvid), wix.com.

Wix is a world leader in the DIY website market. I am responsible for leading a group of developers building <u>Corvid</u>, Wix's serverless platform that lets any developer build a production grade webapp in minutes, with backend code, frontend code, cronjobs, logs, APIs and secret manager.

My job includes:

- o Directly leading 15 developers, team leaders and product managers
- o Planning and executing the engineering work plan
- o Communicating with other teams and external partners
- Hiring
- Public speaking and conferences presence

2017-2018 Head of DevRel and Developer, binaris.com.

Binaris develops low-latency Serverless Function-as-a-Service (FaaS) platform on AWS EC2. As Head of DevRel, I developed open-source low-latency demo apps, wrote the company dev site, built a Serverless meetup group with more than 500 members, founded Israel's first Serverless conference and presented in numerous international conferences.

2014-2017 CTO, vioozer.com, Tel Aviv, Israel.

I built the technology powering a location-based startup from scratch to a full production system with hundreds of thousands of concurrent users. See the <u>website</u>, <u>Android</u> and <u>iOS</u> apps.

- o Lead a team of 5 developers (Mobile, web, backend and, BI) in Israel and US.
- o Built a real-time location-based system receiving location updates from mobile devices and matching questions and answers in real-time. The system includes a backend matching engine, REST API for mobile and web clients, Jenkins CI-CD Pipeline with internal repositories and multiple environments.
- o Tech Stack grep: Ubuntu, Python, Flask, Ubuntu, Apache Storm, AWS, S3, Redis, PostgreSQL, PostGIS, git, AWS Lambda, CDNs, Jenkins, Android (Java), GeoPy, Firebase, RabbitMQ, JUnit, M/Monit, Nginx, Microservices

2012-2013 Java developer, Yahoo!, Ramat Gan, Israel.

Developed fast ad matching technology in Yahoo's Creative Innovation Center team.

- o Developed internal real-time services for fast ad matching with geographical and demographic matching techniques, and a real-time sliding window storage solution for billions of monthly queries over MySQL on Yahoo's internal infrastructure.
- o Created a CI-CD pipeline that reduced the weekly deployment time by 70% and minimized code freezes.
- o Tech Stack grep: Java, Gradle/Maven, Open Stack, MySQL, Protobuf, Solr

2009-2012 Infrastructure developer, Waze.com, Raanana, Israel.

Algorithmic improvements of large databases, server maintenance, and system architecture design.

- Scaled up the daily map improvement process based on app location updates, using geo isolation algorithms and multiprocessing techniques.
- o Created a two-way map merge tool for exchanging map data with external partners.
- o Tech Stack grep: AWS, Python, GIS, PostGIS, PostgreSQL, shell

Education

2005-2009 B.Sc., Hebrew University, Jerusalem.

Major in Computer Science, Minor in the <u>Amirim humanities Honors program</u>. Final project: Analyzing high-MCC functions in the Linux kernel, guided by Prof. Dror Feitelson.

Community Activities

2016- Reversim Summit, Volunteering organizer.

Organized one of the <u>largest community conferences in Israel</u>, coordinating a team of 25 volunteers, 53 speakers and 925 unique visitors. Lead the entire conference in 2016, the content team in 2017 and moderated a track in 2018.

2018.05 Serverless Days TLV, Founder and Organizer.

Organized Israel's first Serverless conference, <u>Serverless Days TLV</u>, an international developer conference with 220 attendees from Israel, Europe, and the US.

2018- Serverless Nights TLV, Meetup Group Organizers.

Founded <u>Serverless TLV</u>, Israel's leading Serverless meetup group, with 60-100 attendees on our monthly meetups. Curated and moderated speakers and content.

Public Speaking

- 2019.09 FITC Web Unleashed Toronto, Building a Serverless, Production-Ready Web App in 45 Minutes.
- 2019.06 Reversim Summit 2019, Demystifying git: from SHA to interactive rebase.
- 2019.03 Redis Day Tel Aviv, Stateful and Stateless: Serverless apps with Redis.
- 2019.02 Serverless TLV meetup, <u>Serverless websites</u>.
- 2018.10 Serverless Days Milano, Think Functions.
- 2018.09 Serverless TLV Meetup, <u>Think Functions</u>, (Hebrew).
- 2018.07 Serverlessconf San Francisco, Think Functions, with Avner Braverman.
- 2018.04 Reversim Podcast, Episode 340: Serverless with Adam Matan(Audio, Hebrew).
- 2018.02 ServerlessConf Paris, Sub-second CI CD pipeline with FaaS, with Avner Braverman.

Military service

1999-2003 IDF Armored Corps tank platoon leader. Retired as a lieutenant.

2005-Present IDF Armored Corps Res. Major. 2i/c in a tank company.